Life Career - Clemens Anzmann

Personal Details

I'm a software developer who loves to create products that help people explore exciting data. My educational background is in digital media, which I studied at the Cork Institute of Technolgy and Hochschule Darmstadt. My master thesis was on data sonfication in the workplace, which I researched a London-based startup. After receiving my degree, I stayed with the startup company and began my journey as a software developer with a passion for data. I am now working for Neo4j on the graph visualisation application Bloom. When I'm not writing code, I enjoy making music and photography.

You can find me on my \bullet <u>GitHub</u> \bullet <u>Twitter</u> \bullet <u>LinkedIn</u> \bullet <u>Website</u>

Work Experience

Role	Company	Time	Туре
Software Engineer Software Engineer building the graph visualisation application Bloom.	Neo4j	Since 01/2019	Full-time
Senior Data Visualisation Engineer Engineer to provide visualisations to make complex information and data sets understandable through rich visual formats that are insightful and actionable, while functioning as an integrator between business needs and technology solutions, helping to create new visualisations based on search concepts.	<u>EmpathyBroker</u>	10/2017 - 12/2018	Full-time
Data Visualisation Engineer Engineer to help uncover insights and tell stories using data with a main focus on using visualisation to tell stories internally and externally. Also making sure that all data that is needed to make important decisions is collected.	Kahoot!	09/2015 - 10/2017	Full-time
Data Experience Engineer Engineer to automate and visualise data flows within DataShaka to its users by building web applications with C# and JavaScript within a ASP.Net framework while maintaining data pipelines in PowerShell on Microsoft Azure.	<u>DataShaka</u>	09/2014 - 09/2015	Full-time

Skills

- Languages & libraries: JavaScript TypeScript React Jest Jasmine d3.js web-gl Plot.ly Echarts Node.js TestCafe Python pandas matplotlib C# SQL Cypher Bash PowerShell
- Software: AWS Google Cloud Microsoft Azure Neo4j Jupyter Looker Google Analytics Amplitude Unity Tableau Microsoft Excel
- Design: Data Visualisation Interface & Interaction design User Experience Testing & Design

Education

Degree	Institute	Time	Course
Master of Arts (M.A.)	Hochschule Darmstadt	09/2011 – 03/2014	Media Direction
ERASMUS student	Cork Institute of Technology	09/2011 – 06/2012	Multimedia Final Year Course
Bachelor of Arts (B.A.)	Hochschule Darmstadt	09/2008 – 06/2011	Digital Media

Training & Conferences

Institute	Time	Course
<u>OpenVisConf</u>	05/2018	"Conference centered around the practice of visualizing data with open source tools on the web"
Visualising Data	03/2017	<u>Data Visualisation & Infographic Design Workshop</u>
PlotCon	11/2016	"The world's most visionary conference for data visualization"
Royal Statistical Society	06/2016	Basic Statistics

Favorite Books

- Edward R. Tufte, "The Visual Display of Quantitative Information" and "Envisioning Information"
- Kyle Simpson, "You Don't Know JS" Series
- Robert Cecil Martin, "The Clean Coder: A Code of Conduct for Professional Programmers"
- Andy Hunt, "The Pragmatic Programmer" and "Pragmatic Thinking and Learning"